realityblurred.com 2019-04-02

# privacy policy – reality blurred

_reality blurred_ , a web site located at realityblurred.com, is owned and operated by Andy Dehnart, who values your privacy. [Learn more about the site here.](https://www.realityblurred.com/realitytv/about/)

This privacy policy outlines the types of personal information that may be received or collected by this site, and how it is used.

You can request that realityblurred.com erase any personal data held about you. That does not include any data realityblurred.com is obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes.

If you have any questions about this privacy policy, please feel free to send a message.

## Information you voluntarily submit

If you choose to submit personal information, such as by contacting realityblurred.com, we may collect the information you submit.

At no time should you submit any sensitive personal or confidential information to realityblurred.com via any method. If you elect to submit such information, realityblurred.com cannot be held responsible for it.

### Contacting reality blurred

There are [several ways you may contact realityblurred.com](https://www.realityblurred.com/realitytv/contact/), including by sending an e-mail or text message. If you choose to contact the site, your message may, of course, include your information, such as your name, e-mail address, and/or phone number. Any personal contact information you choose to share will only be used to respond to you.

If you are sharing information for publication or for the purposes of realityblurred.com’s editorial content, that information may be published, and it may be attributed to you using your name.

Your personal information, such as your e-mail address or phone number, will not be publicly shared, unless you explicitly request that it be shared. And information submitted via the contact form or other methods will never be used for marketing purposes.

### Comments

If you choose to comment on a realityblurred.com story, you’ll be using Spot.IM, a commenting service embedded on some realityblurred.com pages. The information you disclose in comments and your Spot.IM profile is up to you. You may delete your comments through your Spot.IM account at any time.

Refer to [Spot.IM’s privacy policy](https://www.spot.im/privacy/) for details about what information they may collect, and how it is used.

If you choose to link your Spot.IM account to Facebook or another Internet account, other users may see your username, profile picture, and other information.

### Contests

If you choose to enter a contest, contest information, such as a mailing address or e-mail address, will be used only as specified in the contest rules, such as to verify eligibility or to send you a prize, and may be provided to a third party or sponsor in order to send that prize. After the contest concludes, all personal information will be permanently deleted.

### Newsletter

If you choose to [subscribe to realityblurred.com’s e-mail newsletter](https://www.realityblurred.com/realitytv/connect/), your e-mail address will be used to send you that newsletter. Newsletters are sent using TinyLetter, which stores your e-mail address in order to send you those messages.

You can unsubscribe any time, using the link found in every message. Unsubscribing will permanently remove your e-mail address from realityblurred.com’s list of newsletter subscribers.

### Children’s information

None of the content here is directed toward persons under eighteen years of age, and you should exit this site if you are under 18. If a parent or guardian becomes aware that their child has provided realityblurred.com with personally identifiable information without their consent, that parent or guardian should contact us. If we become aware that a child under thirteen has provided us with personally identifiable information, we will remove such information from our files.

## Information that may be collected

### Analytics and logs

realityblurred.com uses Google Analytics to track usage of the website and information about visitors, such as pages that were visited or what web browsers people are using to visit the site. Any data that’s gathered will not be linked to any information that is personally identifiable, and your IP address will be anonymized by Google Analytics.

In order to ensure network and information security and prevent fraud, the web servers that host realityblurred.com may generate and store access, usage, and/or error logs, which may include IP addresses of visitors to the site. Only authorized personnel have access to those sever logs, and they are automatically deleted after seven days.

### Cookies

Cookies may be set in your browser when you visit this website, including by third-party services and as described elsewhere in this Privacy Policy, in order to support advertising, social sharing, and other functions.

You can, at any time, prevent the setting of cookies by changing the settings in your web browser, including by permanently denying the setting of cookies. Furthermore, you may delete already set cookies at any time via your browser or other software programs.

### Embedded content from other websites

Articles on this site may include embedded content, such as YouTube or Facebook videos; tweets from Twitter; or comments from Spot.IM. Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as you’ve visited that website.

Those websites may collect data about you, use cookies to provide their content, embed additional third-party tracking, and/or monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracing your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.

### Affiliate programs

realityblurred.com has affiliate marketing links—including for Amazon Associates and ShareASale—in some of its stories and pages, in order to earn commission-based revenue. If you click on one of these links, a cookie may be placed in your browser to track any sales, in order to provide realityblurred.com with commissions. No personally identifiable information will be received by realityblurred.com about any such affiliate purchases.

### Advertising

realityblurred.com uses third-party advertising networks and companies to serve advertisements when you visit the site, and those services may use cookies. The site has partnered with Mediavine, which uses third-party ad providers. Visit [Mediavine’s list of partners](https://www.mediavine.com/gdpr/) for information on what may be collected and how to opt-out.

You may also:

  * Control Google’s ad personalization by visiting [Google Ads Settings](https://www.google.com/settings/u/0/ads).
  * Opt out of that data collection via [optout.networkadvertising.org](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/)
  * Opt out via the Digital Advertising Alliance’s [WebChoices Tool](http://optout.aboutads.info/)

realityblurred.com uses Google Surveys, which asks you a few market research questions in order to give you free access to premium content and to provide realityblurred.com with revenue. Answers are anonymous and not connected to personally identifiable information, nor are they used to show ads to you. realityblurred.com does not have access to your answers nor know what you’ve been asked; all answers are aggregated with other anonymous answers before being provided to the company or person who paid for the survey. You may choose “Show me a different question” or “Skip survey” if you are uncomfortable with the questions. The “Info” link at the bottom of the survey has details about how the surveys work.

As a result of your visit to realityblurred.com, third-party ad server and traffic monitoring companies—including advertising networks and exchanges, traffic measurement service providers, marketing-analytics service providers, and others—may collect anonymous data. In addition, third-party advertising companies may use non-personally identifiable information about your visits to this and other websites in order to provide relevant ads. Other technologies, such as cookies, JavaScript, or web beacons, may also be used by the third-party ad networks to measure the effectiveness of their advertisements and/or to personalize the advertising content that you see.

Google, as a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on realityblurred.com. Google’s use of the DoubleClick cookie enables it and its partners to serve ads to users based on their visit to realityblurred.com and other sites on the Internet.

realityblurred.com itself has no access to or control over these cookies that are used by third-party advertisers. realityblurred.com’s privacy policy does not apply to, and we cannot control the activities of, such other advertisers or web sites.

### Who your data is shared with

As noted elsewhere in this Privacy Policy, realityblurred.com uses third-party services to provide content and services to you. We may also share your information with third parties when you explicitly authorize us to share your information.

Each third-party service provider’s use of information is dictated by their respective privacy policies. realityblurred.com currently uses these third-party service providers:

  * [TinyLetter/MailChimp](https://tinyletter.com/site/legal/privacy/), to send newsletters to those who choose to subscribe
  * [Spot.IM](https://www.spot.im/privacy), for comments and discussion about stories
  * [AddtoAny](https://www.addtoany.com/privacy), which offers an easy way to share articles via social networks
  * [Google Surveys](https://support.google.com/360suite/surveys/answer/2375134?hl=en&ref_topic=6194669), which asks anonymous market research questions to generate revenue
  * [Google Analytics](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/2763052?hl=en), to track usage of the site
  * reCAPTCHA, which verifies that humans are submitting form content, and is subject to Google’s [privacy policy](https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/) and [terms of use](https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/terms/)

### How long your data is retained, and your rights

  * E-mail addresses for newsletter subscriptions are kept until you unsubscribe.
  * Messages you send to realityblurred.com may be kept indefinitely.
  * Contest entries are kept until one week after the conclusion of the contest.
  * IP addresses in server log files are deleted after seven days.
  * Data you submit to a third-party service, such as comments left on Spot.IM, is subject to those services’ privacy and data retention policies.

If you have chosen to submit personal data, you can request any data you have provided, and can also request that realityblurred.com erase any personal data we hold about you. That does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes.

### Other important things you should know

Except when required by law, realityblurred.com will not sell, distribute, or reveal your personal information without your consent. However, in rare circumstances, realityblurred.com may disclose some or all of your personally identifiable information to the government, law enforcement officials, or private parties if we, in our sole discretion, believe it necessary or appropriate to comply with the law; to respond to legal complaints; to comply with a legal process (including subpoenas); to protect the rights of realityblurred.com and/or its agents; to ensure the safety of the public or any person; and/or to prevent or stop any illegal, unethical, or legally questionable activity.

realityblurred.com may also need to disclose or transfer personal information collected here to third parties who acquire all or part of the site, or in connection with any proceeding brought by or against the site.

### Changes to this policy

If realityblurred.com’s information practices change at some time in the future, policy changes will be posted to this page. Thanks for reading.

 _Updated: May 25, 2018_
